Welcome back. So now let's start with
the stateful processing nodes.
Okay. So stateless is done and let's
start with the stateful.
So stateful processing node is a node
that must remember information from
previous record to produce correct
output.
A stateful operation use ros DB to store
intermediate state. Common example is
count record per key sum amount per
user. So
I would say that the prerequisite for it
is again a Kafka stream architecture.
From there I have explained that that
each task maintain their own ros DB.
Okay. Each task maintain their own rox
DB and they use this DB Rox DB to
maintain the intermediate state. For
example, you have record one, record
two, record three, record four. Okay?
And this is the topology
we are writing.
Now at any point of time, our task is to
count record
by user one. So this is user one, user
two, user one, user three.
Now if you have certain use case like
count record by user one then definitely
you have to store certain information
right let's say record one comes
somewhere you have to store so that's
ros db
so the key is let's say user one count
let's say currently one then record two
comes
user two record one then again user one
record come user one now record become
two. So like this. So this is now a
stateful operation.
Why? Because it remembers information
from the previous record to produce the
correct output.
So these are some of the important
stateful operations. Okay. Yeah. group
by key and group by is not a specific
stateful operation but you can say that
it's a uh it provide an entry point to
stateful processing without this it
would be difficult
so let's start and things will get more
clear
the first thing the group by key and the
group by it has two major
responsibilities
the first is convert your K stream into
K grouped stream what does that mean?
So now understand that when you have a K
stream
you have a key you have a value. Okay.
Now I am saying that the first task or
first responsibility of when we use
group by key and group by is to convert
this to K
grouped stream.
What does it mean? So the first thing it
does is that when we have to do a group,
when we do a group of records,
what should
be the key used?
What should be the key key used?
If the [snorts] same key whatever it is
coming that can be used or a different
key need to be used.
Okay. So if the same key has to be used
use group by key. If you have to use
different key group by okay we'll see an
example.
The second thing it does is repartition
if required.
So I told you the first is it find out
or you can say that it tells the
downstream downstream
nodes processing nodes in after below
this group by whatever we will do below
this processing nodes it tells that
which key you should use for grouping
for grouping the records. The second I
told you that it loop repartition
repartition in the sense that if the key
is change earlier it was let's say order
id and let's say using select key in the
previous video I have told you about
stateful processing right uh stateless
processing in that we have discussed map
value select key so using map and select
key we can change the key so if you have
changed the key means you are eligible
for repartition. Now when you are doing
group by or group by key or group by you
are specifically saying that hey we have
to do a repartition
because earlier it was you if you have
watched the architecture video you might
already get cleared why a repartition is
required because let's say earlier order
ID
and let's say this record has user ID
1 and certain order
just in let's say topic one similarly in
topic two you have an order id but again
it's a user ID one only but certain
different order so earlier
our key was order ID okay so this is
order ID let's say one this is order ID
let's say something 100
so because of this order id topics they
were grouped into a particular topic
Let's say all same order id let's say
key goes into the same partition we know
that same partition you can say that
partition partition partition one
partition two but now we are changing
that hey change the key from order ID
change it to user ID
so that's why repartition is required
because now when you want this user ID
you want all the user ID with particular
ID which are currently scattered into
different partition
Now you have to regroup it so that they
can be part of one partition and reason
I have explained into this architecture
also. Check this out.
Okay. So first is group by key. Group by
key tells the downstream stateful
operation to use existing key for
aggregation itself. So whatever let's
say this is orders K stream.
Now if you are using group by key here
you are just telling downstream whatever
the let's say count aggregate whatever
the other stateful processing nodes you
are just saying that whatever the case
stream I have use this only don't change
it so use it when the current key is
already the key you want to aggregate
for example we have already seen that
during stateless processing nodes order
dot select key if I have to change it.
Let's say I have changed it. Okay,
group by key doesn't know about it. I
have changed it. Now on top of this
I am doing group by key. Now what
happened?
I haven't provided which key to use. So
this group by key does two things. First
tells the downstream that what key to be
used. Now it is saying that I am using
order by use user this case stream
reference right so whatever the key is
use that so whatever the key is coming
use that second is
does repartition required
so here in this case earlier your orders
orders were based on order id so we have
using select key we have changed it and
if you remember from the stateless
processing video I told that whenever
key is changed it is eligible for
repartition but not happened. So but
when group by key is called it check
does key change. Yes earlier it was
order ID now it's user ID. So key is
change. So it initiate the repartition.
Okay. So it initiate the repartition
first and then
the future
whatever the downstream processing nodes
like count aggregate they know that
which key to be used the same key
whatever it is present
okay
the second is group by so group by say
that hey I don't want to use the current
key I will tell you new key which could
be different type two So now let's say I
haven't used select key before. Okay, I
you have only have orders.
Now you can do orders.g group by this is
now your key. This is now value. Now you
can say which key you want to use.
Okay.
So you got a k grouped stream output
this type
your new key and the value.
So it's like
you understood right when we are using
group by key we don't have an way to
change the key you can say that when we
are using group by we can change the
key. So if you have to use a group by
key and you have to change the key then
you have before that you have to make
make use of select key or map. Okay. But
if you don't want to use that, you can
directly use group by and change the
key. And let's say you don't have to
change the key itself. Whatever it is
present in orders orders, you have to
use that itself. You don't have to
change the key itself. Then go back
group by key itself. Direct orders
do.group by key. Okay. So in that case
key is not changed. So no repartition
will happen. And we have already tell
the downstream stateful processing node
that use the existing key. So it will
use whatever the orders
have the key.
Okay. But with the group by we are
specifically telling what key need to be
used. So this become our
new key.
Okay.
So for both group by key and group by if
there is any change in key Kafka stream
need to redistribute records which is a
repartition according to the new key.
Got it?
Count
counts counts the number of record for
each key. That's you can say that when
we do group by key or group by when we
use that many times we confuse that they
are the one actually doing the grouping
but I never told this one in my
understanding group by and group by key
only does two thing. I told you it guide
the downstream
which key to use for grouping. So
downstream does the grouping part. Don't
get confused by this name group by that
they are doing a grouping like in SQL
they are not doing the grouping. They
are just guiding you can say that it's a
meta data it has the metadata which
downstream processing node will use that
which key to do use for grouping. So
count is the one which actually does
doing the grouping.
So it counts the number of record for
each key. So that's where it K table
comes into the picture. So in the K
table you know that it maintains a Rox
DB. Now the counts
this will get invoked on top of this
your K group.
Let's say group doers dot count. So now
it knows which key to use.
Okay. So based on that key
it it maintain the K table. So it key
and let's say value 1 2 3. So long. So
count we do count. Okay.
So orders dot group by key. What does it
mean? Orders. So group by key I am using
means I don't want to change the key.
Whatever the key is present into this
order K stream use that itself. Okay.
Dot count
and you know that dot count
make use of Rox DB. Okay. So that's
where
this is another
method. So either you simply use dot
count or if you want to give a specific
names to your Rox DB you can do that. I
have already shared that also. So I'm
just telling that materialized
this is optional. By default key value
store is used only for the Rox DB
what should be the name of your ROG DB.
Order counter store I have given. And
you know that when we write into the rog
DB the data is stored as bytes. So what
should be the key and the value?
Okay. Uh you can say that serializer in
that we have already covered the
serializer derializer also. So I think
this should be properly clear. So here
if you see that we have already covered
serializers d serializers already.
So dot count and this is what your rod
db properties you can say that it's rog
db name and the key and the value
serializer
clear
now what would happen so I'm just taking
a use case when we do a count now our
topology is let's say this source topic
from this we got a orders this is our k
stream Okay. Then on top of it itself we
do group by key. When we do a group by
key on this seam mean no repartition
happen. The same key I am using but I
get this object K group.
Now on top of it I called count.
So count will do it will rock read the
ros DB update the count and write it
value also.
So because it handles the ROD DB let's
say user one
it will read it whatever the value it is
it will update and write it also it keep
on updating this
okay similarly if there is a repartition
let's say source topic you have done a
select key okay and when you do a group
by key it will initiate a repartition
and uh then you do a count same flow
nothing different I just tell you that
uh the same the count which we are doing
can either be a this scenario or this
scenario repartition scenario no
repartition scenario but only thing is
you don't have to worry about that
repartition is handled internally which
we have discussed in architecture video
okay so this is just an example I have
shown you let's say orders
dot group by
now I have changed the key order dot get
user id dot count
so earlier input record was this let's
say this is the input record now in this
ros db which count will maintain so it
would be user id based the key would be
your user ID so count
will use the information which group by
metadata provides
Which key to use this key? User ID.
Okay. So, user one, user one, user one.
So, three and user two has only one
record
long output is this. Generally, this is
your key. This is your value.
Clear? Very very simple. Similarly, we
have aggregate. So, sometimes you have
to decide how the aggregation should
work. So, that's where you can use it
too. That means you want to write your
own logic. So just see this understand
this aggregate method then you can use
it very easily. So if you see this
aggregate
the first parameter it has is
initializer. This is the first
parameter. Initializer means when you
see the key for the first time how do
you want to initialize it? Whether you
want to initialize with zero or if let's
say if you're using a string then with
empty or null whatever when you identify
a key for the first time how you want to
initialize
and the second is aggregator if you go
inside an aggregator function interface
what it has k v and this three parameter
it has
what does this three parameter is key
this is key this is value what is this
third one. So third one here if you see
so this is your key this is your value
and this third one is your ultimately
your return type what actually you going
to return
okay the same thing it going to come and
now here if you see
the output k table
ka vr so this is your key this is
actually your new value.
This is VR is actually your new value.
So now read this fully again. Initialize
what is the type generate type V R.
Okay. So means now just connect the dots
here. I know at one time it would be
look difficult like we are using
function interface plus generics. So
it's difficult but connect the dots here
in the initialized plus this it will get
clear. Let me
yeah read it again.
The first is initializer. Now here if
you see initializer the generic type we
are passing is VR. Now here if you see
the VR is nothing but a return type. So
this is your Rox DB. what is present
inside a ros db that will go okay now
this vr is getting passed here so this
is your ros db value
so now in the aggregator we have three
key
value and your rocks db value
now whatever you have to do the
operation do it and ultimately what you
are returning is the third one itself
the your rocks
DB value you are returning and the same
this VR the same is getting updated into
your K table your ROS DB value
see this example it will get clear let's
say this is the value this is the
records output we want is allies 300 Bob
500 so allies has let's say order 100
150 50 so combine 300 and for Bob 200
and 300 total 500 this should come.
So first is this orders dotg group by
key. Yes this is my let's say earlier
Kstream orders
key value. So key is this value is this
I want this is a metadata all the
downstream use the same key. So use this
name as a your key itself. Okay. So I
got this object k grouped stream key
value.
Now on this I am calling dotaggregate.
Now parameters
the first is initializer. We have to
provide an implementation for this
method. It takes zero parameter. So zero
parameter
and what should be the output. So
initializer in the sense is when you see
the key for the first time how you want
to initialize it. Let's say the allies
has come for the first time. How you
want to initialize it in the Rox DB zero
I and assign the value zero. So
initially allies is zero in let's say in
Rox DB.
Okay.
Now aggregator key value and what's the
Rox DB value comes in let's say so key
value and this value generally give it a
name total from Rox DB till now do
whatever your computation would be into
for this one I am just doing whatever
the value present in Rox DB plus the
total order amount now okay and the same
get return here
okay inside this
Now example is let's say first time
allies came currently Rox DB has no data
ros DB lookup not found so initializer
would be zero and then your aggregator
will run aggregator will do 0 plus the
record this is coming right 0 + 100. So
this aggregator will do this is your key
this is your value and this is the
currently Rox DB value. So it will do 0
+ 100. So ultimately it will return 100
which will ultimately get stored into
the Rox DB and also return here.
Okay. Now second time record come it
will do a DB lookup. Yes. Allies has a
value. Yes it found 100. So will it run
the initializer? No value is present. So
directly it will go to the aggregator
key value and the Rox DB value currently
100. So it will do 100 plus order dot
get amount 150. So it will return 250
and 250 also you have here.
So third record the same ultimately
return 300. So
allies has 300 into the rox DB also.
Got it? So if you want a control over
your aggregation logic you can do it
yourself because if you use count it
would be just like allies three but you
want to count this amount so you can use
aggregate your logic
right and another is very important is
join
so k stream. So if you remember that
we have different type of source you can
say K stream K table okay now K stream U
means infinite stream what's the start
when the stream start when the stream
finish you don't know data keep on
coming data keep on flowing but K table
K table maintains
key value Okay, let's say user one its
latest record,
user two its latest record. It has
maintained certain information. We have
already seen that into the source also.
Now let's say how you want to join it.
A k stream cable join and reach each
stream event with the latest value from
a table. Okay. So I am saying from
stream to join from stream to K table we
are doing a joining. So K table let's
say has user address information and now
the order is coming let's say order ID 1
user ID
U00
user ID is 100
so you need the address detail of it so
you are joining the K table finding from
this user ID that hey what is the
address detail now this address detail
now you are enriching it here in this
order itself So you have a new order
object you can say that
very simple just understand when we do a
join method just under understand this
parameter it would be very easy the
first
the K table which you want to join with.
Okay the first parameter is simple. Now
the second is value joiner. Go inside
this and see what happen. So if you go
inside this value joiner you will see
this method which we have to provide an
implementation. The first is your value
one v_sub_1 which is nothing but a k
stream value.
So you are joining k stream versus k
table right. So it is just like
let's say user 100 the key you can say
the k stream value
and the second latest value for the key
from the k table.
Okay so for the exact key see join
happens on the key basis. Understand
that when we are doing join internally
it make use of key here and key here to
do the joining. Now after that it has
done the joining it get the data
correct. So this v_sub_1 value one is
the value of this k stream this value
let's say u00 whatever the value we got
this represent this
v2
represent
the data value
for this u00 key
okay whatever the value it represent the
value from the k table
join happens between the key of both.
Okay. Once you have a join. So now let's
say K stream
user ID U00
order id something K table
U certain data. Now this order comes. So
you do join. So it will use the key.
So you make sure that whatever the K
stream you have its key and this K table
key should be same then only your join
will work. Okay. So now let's say that
its key key is user ID. It key should be
user. If it is order ID change it change
it to user ID then only it should work.
Okay. So now let's say key is user ID. K
table key is also this user ID which is
U. So based on this U join will happen.
So it has this complete information of
this record. It has this complete
information of this record. So this
V_sub_1 represent a value
for the K record of this K stream. This
V_sub_2 represent a value
from this K table for this key. Okay.
Now whatever you want it how you want to
append or how you want to enrich you
want to create a new object do whatever
and return the new object and this new
object is ultimately become your so here
if you see
the key this new object ultimately this
VR becomes your new value so you are
enriching
the Kstream data see this example it
will get Here I have a case stream
orders dot select key. So earlier order
was on order id that's why I change it
first to select key and I am using user
id because my k table is based on user
ID. So I have a k table I have a k
stream now I'm doing a join order by
users
orders by user dot join on which k table
users. So internally they will use the
key of the both. Okay. Now this is the
value from the K stream. This is the
value from the K table. How you want to
enrich you can create a total new
object. How you wanted it totally your
logic. But whatever you want to return
new object or the same object order but
with additional which has additional
field you have earlier was null now you
have filled it. Do whatever and return
that one. So now your next
K stream is ready with this key and this
enrich order. Now you can build on top
of this. Got it?
So key for both K stream and K table
should be same.
Similarly you can do K table to K table
very similar. So I have two K table.
Okay. Now you can do profiles dot
preferences. Profile dot join
preferences. Now this is the value from
the profile. This is the value from the
preference your logic how you want to
create a new object. Okay. And that
ultimately would be your new
K table because K table K table output
is K table. And here we are doing a
joining with K stream to K table. So
means we are enriching K stream. Okay.
We are just using K table as a source
like whatever the object is coming using
it key find out the data enriching it
and now we have a more enriched object.
Okay.
But
K table to K stream is not possible.
Why? Because Kstream is an unbounded
sequence of event.
There is no start end. We can't just
randomly look up. So this is not
possible. I think it's clear right? K
table you have a certain table right you
are maintaining it but the stream is
like no start no end how the join will
work
cool
so clear stateful operations these are
mostly used and there could be many but
yeah the main main one I have covered it
the last which left is
window
last 5 minutes last 10 minutes last one
are counted count the order okay so
that's is left after that our K stream
is totally finished okay
okay guys any doubt let me know we can
disc sorry we can discuss further Bye.